Now that we have looked at how single-link clustering works,
我们之前已经看过了单连接聚类法是怎样运作的
let's take a minute to compare it
我们现在用一点时间 用我们之前看过的数据集
with k-means on these datasets that we've looked at before.
把它和 K-均值聚类法做个比较
So, for the first one,
第一个数据集
k-means seemed to do a better job at breaking down
K-均值聚类法似乎更能够把这些均匀分布的数据
this uniformly distributed datasets into three clusters.
分成三个类
While in single-link, we can see that one drawback of
而单连接聚类法则有一个缺陷
one cluster eating up the entire dataset and then two clusters being small.
一个类几乎囊括了整个数据集 仅剩两个非常小的类
So, it seems that k-means does a better job in this case.
所以 这个案例中 K-均值聚类法更有效
With the two crescents,
在双月牙形数据集中
single-link is able to carve them out perfectly.
单连接聚类法能够完美地把两个类分离出来
This is because these datasets are close to each
这是因为这些数据集彼此靠近
other and then there's a good amount of separation between the two crescents.
两个数据集之间有足够的间隙
And so, this is a case where a single-ink does better than k-means.
所以 这个案例中 单连接聚类法比 K-均值聚类法更有效
Two rings is another really well-done job for a single-link.
双环形数据集中 同样 单连接聚类法更有效
It carves them out beautifully.
完美地将类分离出来
We have the inside ring and
我们得到一个内环 一个外环
the outside ring as the two clusters that we were looking for.
这两个类恰恰是我们要找的类
In this dataset here,
在这个数据集中
k-means does a better job here.
K-均值聚类法更有效
We have one cluster that went and ate up everything.
一个类几乎囊括了所有数据
So, not the best job for single-link here.
所以这个案例中 单连接聚类法不是最佳选择
This is not the best job as well, I mean,
这个也不是最佳选择
but it's able to carve this one out,
但是它能够将这个类分离出来
but this cluster of one point is not really very meaningful or helpful to us.
但是这个类只有一个点 对我们来说没有多大意义 没多大帮助
And with this, it does the same job that k-means did.
这个案例中 单连接聚类法和 K-均值聚类法效果一样
But there is one additional thing that we can get out of this,
但我们能从中额外得到一点信息
which we've discussed before,
这也是我们之前讨论过的
is the hierarchies or the dendrograms that result from this.
就是由此产生的层次或系统树
So, let's look at them.
我们来看一下
So, with this uniform,
在这个均匀分布的图中
we can see, this is how it looks.
我们能看到它的层次是这样的
And we don't really get much information from the hierarchy here.
但我们从中得不到什么信息
We can kind of tell that there are no clear clusters that
只能看出 我们没有办法把这个数据集
we can break the datasets down into.
分离出清晰明显的类
With the two crescents,
在双月牙形数据集中
we can see that there is one cluster here and then another cluster here,
我们能看到 这儿有一个类 这儿也有一个类
and they're separated by a lot of distance.
这两个类被足够的空隙分离开来
And while we can tell that visually by looking at this one graph here,
通过观察这个图表
one thing that's important is that,
我们能发现重要的一点
what if our dataset had three,
如果我们的数据集有三个维度
or four, or 10, or 100 dimensions?
四个维度 十个维度 甚至一百个维度呢？
We will not be able to graph it into dimensions like
我们就不能把它绘制成这样的图表
this and just easily be able to visually tell that they're separated.
只能简单地从视觉上判定 它们之间是彼此分离的
But no matter how many dimensions we have,
但不管有多少个维度
we can produce a dendrogram into dimensions that would look exactly like this.
我们得到的系统树都能分成这样的维度
And so, this is a real valuable way for us to be able to visualize datasets,
所以 这是种非常有价值的方式 能帮我们对数据集做视觉化处理
even if they have multiple dimensions.
即便是有多个维度的数据集也可以
With the two rings, we can also see the two structures clearly here,
针对双环形数据集 我们也能清楚地看到有两个结构
separated by a lot of distance.
这两个结构间有充足的间隙
So, this is very useful.
所以 这个方法非常有用
I love this example.
我喜欢下面这个例子
So, well, single-link was not able to find,
单连接聚类法并不能
and this cluster has one closer,
把这个类定义为一个类
and I define this point,
把这个点
this group, as another cluster, let's say.
或者这个组群 定义为另一个类
In the hierarchy, you can see that there are three structures.
在这个层次图中 你能看到现在有三个结构
Even if the direct result is not indicative of the three clusters that you want,
尽管直接结果显示的并不是我们我们要找的三个类
the dentrogram actually tells you something,
但这个系统树图仍然告诉了我们一些信息
that maybe you if can experiment a little bit,
或许你尝试一下
maybe try other hierarchical clustering methods,
采用其他的层次聚类法
you can be able to isolate three separate clusters.
你能分离出三个单独的类
And this also works very well here.
这对这个例子也同样适用
So, while we wanted to find these three clusters, this is one,
当我们想要找到这三个类的时候 这是类一
and this is two, and this is three,
这是类二 这是类三
it wasn't able to do it,
这个聚类方法并不能实现
but if we look at the dendrogram,
但是如果我们看一下系统树图
we can easily see that.
很容易发现
This seems to be like a cluster,
这看起来像一个类
this seems to be like cluster,
这儿像是一个类
and this seems to be like cluster.
这儿也像是一个类
So, the dendrograms give us
所以 这个系统树图告诉我们
additional insights that maybe the direct results of the clustering misses.
可能聚类方法的直接结果有所缺失
And here, we can see this is a very easy example
这是一个非常简单的例子
where there is a lot of distance separating those three,
这三个类之间有足够间隙
and these two are closer to each other.
这两个类之间距离更近
So, these two are these two structures here.
所以 这两个类指的是图中的这两个结构
And so, this is an examination of
所以 这是一个检验方法
how a single-link compares and how useful these dendrograms can be.
检验单连接聚类法的效果以及这些系统树图的作用
Let's proceed by looking at other types of hierarchical clustering.
我们继续看其他的层次聚类法